# **Rawin Kumar**

# **Front End Developer**

**Residential Address:** C-45, 3<sup>rd</sup> Floor, Mandawli, Delhi – 110092 **Mobile:** 9818771015; **Email:** robinmedco2002@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

1+ year experience in React.js. Finding opportunity where I can expand my knowledge & ability using my programming skills.

6+ years' experience in Web Development. Energetic Web Designer & Developer. Total more than 9+ years' experience in creating & maintaining functional, attractive & responsive websites for various types of industries, including Luxury Hotels, Real Estate & Corporate Companies. Clear understanding of all modern technologies with best design practices. Experience in WordPress Customization & Mobile Application Development (iOS & Android). Basic knowledge of Search Engine Optimization process (SEO). Strong organizational skills to maintain multiple tasks. I Create website layouts/user interface by using standard HTML/CSS practices. Also, I have experience in Graphic Designing & company branding.

A result oriented individual! Expertise is broad in scope. Possess a high technical aptitude and a high level of creativity.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Client account management, handling team independently, interaction with the client and understand their requirements
- Web Applications Development for Mobile & Web
- Design & Development of CMS & ecommerce websites
- Ensuring web site quality, performance and reliability by using third party website like GTmetrix
- Understanding of screen resolutions and how to design for them
- Testing with multiple browsers and operating systems to ensure the best compatibility possible
- Well-versed in Google Analytics
- Experience with search engine optimization (SEO)
- Knowledge of Facebook & email marketing campaign
- Speed optimization

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

- Graduation from Delhi University
- Intermediate from Jharkhand Education Board

## **TECHNICAL QUALIFICATION**

 Dual Diploma Certification in multimedia & Web Engineering from Arena Multimedia, Jamshedpur.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERTISE

- React Js
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- Angular
- Typescript
- jQuery
- WordPress
- XML
- Joomla
- Dreamweaver
- Flash
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premier
- Adobe After Effects
- Cordova
- Xcode
- Eclipse
- SDK
- Node

## AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Team Lead
- Project Handling
- UI/UX Design
- CMS Websites
- e-commerce Websites
- Web Development
- Graphic Design
- Visualization
- Branding
- Mobile App Design
- E-mailers

## **LANGUAGES**

- Hindi
- English

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Front End Developer at ismart Infosoft (Part Time)

(October 2020 - Present)

It's a Digital Marketing & Web Development company, providing web design, web development, social media marketing & SEO services to its clients. In this organization as the senior web designer & developer, my core activities included:

- · Build responsive websites using React js.
- · Web Application designing & Development
- Write coding using HTML, JavaScript, CSS, JSX
- Modify existing code as needed.
- Design new features for existing websites
- Customize themes to meet clients' requirements.
- · Assist in website traffic and performance monitoring.

## Web Developer at Hardev Singh Photography

(March 2015 – July 2020)

This organization works for Luxury Hotels and Real-estate Industry Worldwide. They do Online & offline web applications & mobile app development. In this organization as the senior web designer & developer, my core activities included:

- Responsive Web Development
- Web Application designing & Development, Mobile Application
- Development (iOS & Android), 360 Virtual tour programming.
- Planning site designs, functionality and navigation, along with audience funnels and data capture points.
- Building wireframes & prototypes which were then turned into functional and responsive digital products.
- Handling all composition, colour, typography, and branding for projects.
- Creating landing pages using Angular, Html5, CSS, JavaScript.

#### (April 2014 - March 2015) - Web Designer

- · Responsive Web Designing
- 360 Virtual tours designing.
- Planning site designs, functionality and navigation.
- Handling all composition, colour, typography, and branding for projects.

## Web & Flash Designer at Macro Graphics Pvt. Ltd.

(July 2012 – April 2014)

It's a Print & Web Development company, providing print and web design, web development, Flash Development, Animation & SEO services to its clients. In this organization as the web & flash designer, my core activities included:

- Build websites.
- Web Application designing & Development
- Build Flash based website
- Flash Project

- Flash Animation
- E-learning website
- · Updating and maintaining website

#### Flash Designer at S. Chand Technology Pvt. Ltd

(October 2011 – July 2012)

It's a Book Publishing company, providing print and CBT and WBT Publishing Company. Flash Development, Animation for Study material. In this organization as the flash designer, my core activities included:

- Build CBT.
- Build WBT
- Flash Programming
- Flash Animation
- E-learning website
- Updating and maintaining CBT & WBT
- Audio / video editing

## Flash Designer at Algorithm Infosoft

(October 2010 - October 2011)

It's a Application Development, web Solution and IT Enabled Service companies. The multimedia design division of the Algorithm creates educational interactive CDs. In this organization as the flash designer, my core activities included:

- Build CBT.
- Build WBT
- Flash Programming
- Flash Animation
- Director Animation & Lingo script
- · Updating and maintaining CBT & WBT
- Audio / video editing

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name : Mr. A. P. Gupta

Gender : Male

Date of Birth : 12<sup>th</sup>January 1983

Mobile Number : 9818771015

Marital Status : Married

Date	•••		 			
Place						